# Elise A. Weir, PhD

<u>eliseweir@gmail.com</u> | Memphis, TN 38120 <u>eliseweir.com</u>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software developer with nearly 2 years of experience writing, testing, and delivering back end enterprise microservices integrated closely with RFID and forklift hardware. Experienced mathematician and educator with a proven history of technical adaptability and strong communication skills.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Java Spring Boot, Typescript, Python, C++

Technologies: git, npm, Jenkins, gradle, StencilJS, Angular, Ionic, SQL

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer II, FedEx

2/2021 - current

- Supporting maintenance of the current RFID stack using Java Spring Boot, and adding new functionality including REST endpoints.
- Deploying using continuous integration tools, including Jenkins with GitLab hooks.
   Spinning up a Java Spring Boot app from scratch and integrating with existing REST services.
- Writing pages and components for Android and web as part of a special effort to modernize our forklift application using Angular Ionic with custom Stencil components, testing in Jest, Jasmine, and Cypress.
- Building Angular services to call existing REST endpoints.

## Visiting Assistant Professor, UCSB Dept. of Mathematics

7/2019 - 6/2020

- Served as the primary instructor for large (80 and 160 student) online calculus classes.
- Taught small upper division classes focused on engaging students in logical thinking.
- Directed small teams of Teaching Assistants in holding recitation sections and grading to provide practice and feedback to students.

## **EDUCATION**

## Bootcamp, Web Programming and Code 1.0

9/2021 - 12/2021

Tech901 - tech901.org

- Studied programming basics including logic, functions, and data structures.
- Learned front-end web development in HTML/CSS and JavaScript.

# Doctor of Philosophy, Mathematics

2018

University of Tennessee. Knoxville

Emphasis on linear algebra and geometry, and writing code to try out possible theorems.

#### Bachelor of Science, Honors Mathematics

University of Tennessee, Knoxville

## **PUBLICATIONS**

The Dimension of the Restricted Hitchin Component for Triangle Groups
Doctoral Dissertation available at <a href="mailto:trace.tennessee.edu/utk">trace.tennessee.edu/utk</a> <a href="mailto:graddiss/5089/">graddiss/5089/</a>

8/2018